Sedani Arjun Bhavesh

Senior Software Engineer

- Full stack developer with 3 years 2 months of experience in development on React Native, ReactJS, HTM5, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, NoSQL and various other technologies
- Presently associated with Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solutions
 Private Limited. as Senior Software Engineer since August 2019
- Previously associated with EVRY India Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer from October 2016 -August 2019
- Effective Individual contributor and Team Player Scrum Fundamentals certified in end-to-end SDLC Process (Requirement analysis, System Study, Designing, Coding, Testing, Deployment and Implementation) Understand technical concepts and quick in converting them into meaningful results.
- Exposure to DevOps tools like JIRA, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jenkins and Cli..

Achievements

- Achieved Employee of the Month award for the month of March 2018 for development of chat-bot android application using Amazon Lex within a short duration from the Employer (EVRY India Pvt. Ltd.)
- Honored for "PropertyGram" as among the top 10 innovations at "TECHUTSAV 2019" EVRY's annual technical innovation expo and client meet
- Honored for "Smart Real Estate" as the best innovation at "TECHUTSAV 2018", EVRY's annual technical innovation expo and client meet
- Honored "3-30-300 rule of facility management business" as one of the best ideas at Evry's hackathon 2018

Work History

2019-08

Senior Software Engineer

Current

Robert Bosch Engineering And Business Solution, Bengaluru, Karnataka

Project Name: Health point Hospital Management Portal

- Developed health care theme based web app for clients such as Walmart and Optimis by integrating multiple EMR and hospital management system capable to handle over 4000 clinics and over 2 million Providers across US
- Developed progressive web app compatible with multiple browsers and mobile as well
- Used latest React features like react hooks, ES7 and developing custom hooks
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources
- Consulted with customers to gather requirements and discuss design choices
- Developed landing pages, dashboards and online applications using ReactJS, styled-components and developing common components from scratch

2018-03 - 2019-08

Software Engineer

EVRY India Pvt. Ltd, Bnegaluru, Karnataka

Project 1: Propertygram

About:

Contact

Address

Bengaluru, KA, 560002

Phone

+91-7411931500/+91-7016926698

E-mail

sedaniarjun@gmail.c om

Skills

React Native, Android Native

Excellent

React, HTML5, CSSS, JavaScript, ECMAScript

Excellent

Amazon Lex bot, AWS Lambda function

Very Good

Database: SQLite, NoSQL (DynamoDB, CosmosDB,Firebase)

Very Good

Development IDEs : Android Studio, XCode, Visual Studio Code, PyCharm

Very Good

A-Frame

Very Good

Agile

Excellent

Redux

Excellent

FS₆

Very Good

Automation

Very Good

Automation

 Propertygram is an attempt to build a gamification framework that can be integrated into any property management software to gamify regular tasks in the application. It also provides basic intelligence for task allocation and analytics for measuring property managers efficiency/work life balance and overall building health Responsibilities:

- Developed gamification framework using React Native, Firebase database, Python for Company level Innovation challenge and customer meet during Period 1st January-15th March 2019
- Developing a new framework from scratch to support existing application and data
- Developing modal using ML and Al KNN to predict likes and dislikes of property managers
- Developing new algorithms to make the framework dynamically supporting all data
- Developing reusable components to be used throughout the new version of application

Project 2: 3-30-300 Rule of Facility management About:

 It is a solution that integrates IOT, ML and VR to assist companies to analyze and predict on how to optimize on (rent and utilities) out of utilities (\$3), rent (\$30), and payroll (\$300) which they usually should spend as total expenditure per resource

Responsibilities:

- Developed JavaScript code for integrating ReactJS with A-Frame code using webpack
- Built ML algorithm to calculate space occupancy based on raw sensor data using Python
- Integrating Python and front-end code to Firebase database
- Designed and implemented A-Frame code to showcase analytics and prediction in 3d

Project 3: CBRE Host Mobile

About:

 CBRE Host is a smart building solutions app, one of the premier customers is Nike, which is designed in SAAS model This project includes way finding, people finding, room booking, reminders, creating service requests and tracking status

Technical challenges include integration with multiple CMMS systems, AD and Office Integration

Responsibilities:

- Developing React Native common components using glamorous-native, HTML5,CSS
- Fetching data from Rest APIs using Promise and setting data using Redux
- App navigation using react-navigation and react-hooks
- Implementation of desired functionalities and Unit testing

2018-01 - 2018-03

Associate Software Engineer

EVRY India Pvt. Ltd

Project 1: Smart Real Estate

About:

 Smart Real Estate is a solution that integrates AR and VR to assist real estate companies in creating immersive virtual property tours and Augmented Property information for their end customers and prospects thus helping them feel lifelike simulation of properties from anywhere in the world Responsibilities: Data Structures, Algorithm

Very Good

JavaScript



Natural language processing

Very Good

Languages

Languages : English, Hindi, Gujarati.

- Designed prototype to get get shortlisted in company level tech fest
- Lead the team by guiding team members on how to achieve the goal
- Developed the algorithm for Geolocation based AR in ARCore which serves as a base for any developer to build their own Geolocation AR app
- Developed the reusable JavaScript camera code in A-frame which gives walk through experience in VR

2016-10 - 2017-12

Trainee Software Developer

Evry India Pvt Ltd

Project 1: IDA Connect

About:

 IDA provides voice and chat-based help to customer to answer queries and to perform business operation, understand customer request (voice & chat) in natural language and provide appropriate help. The mobile application is built on Android and uses Amazon Lex SDK to interact with AWS platform for natural language processing, conversation orchestration. The message processing is serviced through AWS Lambda functions

Responsibilities:

- Technology evaluation and self-learning new technologies as required by the project
- Understanding the business logic and analyzing the changes required in language detection and mic automation till the conversation is ended
- Made continuous movement of mic until you get the final response while having voice conversation and movement of mic will stop when we get final response only and hided the keyboard on click of mic button
- Implemented Chatbot for other grids of CBRE
- Bug fixing

Education

2012-08 - 2016-06 Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics And Communications Engineering

NMAMIT, Nitte - Mangalore